Brandon Argel

Frontend Developer

brandonargel.me | brandargel@gmail.com | github.com/BrandonArgel | linkedin.com/in/brandargel | +52 (33) 27161523 | Jal. México

About

Software Developer with experience in frontend technologies such as: React, TypeScript, Next.js, Redux. Interested in high impact projects that allow me to combine different frameworks and technologies, culminating in delivering added value to its users.

Experience

Platzi

Quality Check | July 2022 - May 2023

Contributed to the quality assurance of the content, working together with different teams to deliver a high quality product used by more than 3 million students in Latin America.

- Provide continuous feedback to the team to iterate on better results.
- We reduced the rate of student-reported content errors by 66%.
- Reduced the rate of students affected by content errors by 68%.

SEO team associate | May 2022 - July 2022

Contributed to the creation, revision, and improvement of the content in the platform classes, mainly in technology courses. Creation and continuous improvement of the content for the platform classes.

- We generate quality content for Platzi students.
- We improved the SEO of the platform.
- We create and improve content.

Education

Platzi Master

Frontend Development | January 2022 - Present

Platzi Master is an intensive and elite program, where only 0.01% of the best students on the platform are accepted, to turn them into the next generation of the best professionals in the technology industry, with 1:1 support from specialized and recognized technical trainers in the industry.

Platzi

Technology, English | September 2018 - Present

I am an education enthusiast, so I am constantly learning foreign languages like English, and French, programming languages, and public speaking, as they are tools that will help me share with more people and grow together.

Escuela Politécnica Ing. Jorge Matute Remus

Professional Computer Technologist | August 2017 - July 2021

I studied a career in computer science, where I learned the basics of various programming languages and web development. Also I did internships and professional projects.

Consultora Blockchain

Web Developer | September 2021 - March 2022

Developing a web application for the La Paz, Bolivia mayor's office. Using technologies like JavaScript, SCSS, React, Next.js, Redux-Saga, and other libraries.

- We work on the creation and implementation of the logic of the modules for the users.
- We create flows of citizen participation: voting, creation of proposals, etc.

Axo Systems

Frontend Developer | April 2021 - September 2021

Development and maintenance of code for internal and external client websites using HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, React, Firebase, WordPress, and more.

- Sites manually tested across multiple browsers and mobile devices to ensure cross-browser compatibility and responsiveness.
- Developing high quality websites for internal and external clients.

Skills

Expert

HTML, JavaScript (ES6), Git version control, (S)CSS, responsive design, mobile first, flex, grid.

Advanced

React, Next.js, Redux, Redux-Saga, React Hooks, npm, Typescript, consume REST API, JSON, OOP, Vite.js.

Familiar

Styled Components, Material UI, Antd, NodeJS, Figma, webpack, Python, Express, FastAPI, Angular.

Certifications and courses

- Git & GitHub
- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- React.js
- My profile at Platzi